

## Samuel S. Gibson

919.815.2461

sgibsoncoding@gmail.com star-gibson.github.io/responsive portfolio/ github.com/Star-Gibson www.linkedin.com/in/stargibson/

#### **Profile**

Graduate of the International Studies program at the academically rigorous, North Carolina State University, with proven efficiency in the Chinese language. Currently enrolled in the UNC-Charlotte Coding Bootcamp to gain technical skills in software development that I can combine with my vast knowledge to the technology space from previous opportunities. Upon completion of the program, I look forward to implementing my new skill set and obtaining a role as a Junior Web Developer.

Forward thinking professional with hands on experience in a variety of diverse environments, both in the United States and abroad. Reliable and responsible individual who is able to provide leadership when collaborating with others, but also possesses the mental fortitude to work well independently.

# **Employment History**

ettain group – Charlotte, NC	Technical Recruiter	
ettain group – Raleigh & Charlotte, NC	Resource Specialist	
Cloud Harvest - Raleigh, NC	Account Manager	
Planet Fitness – Cary, NC	Front Desk Supervisor	03.20
WCPSS - Raleigh, NC	Substitute Teacher	

01/2020 - 05/202002/2019 - 01/202001/2018 - 11/20182016 - 2.2017 / 6.2017 - 11.2017

12.2016 - 04.2017

## **Experience**

#### Technical Skills

- > Software Development: JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Bulma, Invision, Github, MomentJS, API Integration
- ➤ Able to create, modify, and utilize Microsoft software (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- > Certified in Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, and Microsoft Powerpoint
- > Adept problem solver
- Reviewed invoices via ABC, QuickBooks and cross-referenced with client billing statements in order to settle any discrepancies.
- ➤ Intermediate level Chinese language skills

#### Communication

- > Fostered relationships with potential candidates in the Raleigh and Charlotte market while supporting Cisco, Bank of America, Wells Fargo, Caring LLC, Pratt & Miller, Lowe's, Harris Teeter, Kroger, Atrium, Premier Inc., Bioventus, and various other clients.
- > Provided insight into opportunities ranging from Help Desk to Director of Business Intelligence, while affording potential qualified candidates the ability to make a change in career.

- Effectively communicated Cloud Harvest's IT asset recovery service to organizations to partners, as well as customers in the efforts to return initial cap-ex as the transition to an op-ex model occurs
- ➤ Initiated and formed partnerships with 10 organizations, with primary focus on partnering with and understanding the AWS (LATAM, US) sales team and cycle.
- Able to generate solutions swiftly to newly encountered situations by implementing the Pause, Acknowledge, Clarify, and Respond technique (P.A.C.R)
- > Communicated and interacted with native Chinese speakers to navigate while abroad
- ➤ Ability to convey teaching points in a purposeful manner to my students

### Global Preparedness

- Traveled abroad to gain new deeper and further my perspectives and understanding of culture: China (7 wks.), Greece (14 days)
- Participated in the International Friendship Program and the Confucius Institute to further my Chinese language skills while improving my understanding of the Chinese language.

## **Projects**

### UltiMUTT Dog Finder - https://marenhamby.github.io/UltiMutt\_dog\_finder/

- The UltiMutt Dog Finder was a collaborative project with the goal of creating an application where users take a quiz to figure out what breed of dogs best match their lifestyle. This application connects with various API's, in which provide the user with information on adoptable dogs, as well as the adoption centers that the dog corresponds with.
- Technology Implemented: Restful APIs, JSON, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and Bulma

### Day Planner - https://star-gibson.github.io/day planner/

- The goal of the Day Planner project was to create a work-day scheduler to help the user plan out their busy day. When interacting with this polished UI you can see that the time-blocks are dynamically updated depending on the time of day.
- Technology Implemented: jQuery, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, Bootstrap4, momentJS

# Password Generator - <a href="https://star-gibson.github.io/password\_generator/">https://star-gibson.github.io/password\_generator/</a>

- The goal of the Password Generator was to create an application that an employee/user could use to generate a random password based on criteria given their answer choices to the modals that pop up upon visiting the site. This application will run in the browser and features a dynamically updated HTML and CSS UI powered by JavaScript.
- > Technology Implemented: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and JSON

#### Education

- ➤ UNC-Charlotte Coding Bootcamp Charlotte, NC (In-Progress)
- ➤ Bachelor of Arts, International Studies: North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC
- Nanjing Normal University: Mandarin Language Immersion, Nanjing, China (Certificate of Completion)
- > Diploma, North Carolina School of Science and Math: Durham, NC